Guide to the Beekman Family Papers 1720-1920's MS 51
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Box 17(B), William Beekman, 1780-1783
  - William Beekman and Family, Correspondence, Accounts, Magdalaine and Catherine and Mary Beekman Rental Execution, 1783 (Box 17(B), Folder 14)
    Items described for Folder 14 in White's guide have been divided into boxes 14 & 15.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Bonds and Mortgages due Magdalaine and Catherine and Mary Beekman, 1783 (Box 17(B), Folder 15)
- Box 18, William Beekman, 1784-1788
  Described in White's guide Volume 1, pages 202 to 210. In every folder there are misc. receipts and some documentation about purchasing, buying or renting property.
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Correspondence, Local Senate-Assembly Vote in Outward of NYC, 1784 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Correspondence, Hampden Hall Documents, Catherine-Mary-Magdalen Accounts, Catherine Beekman Slave Sale, 1785 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    For more on Hampden Hall real estate, see Box 17(B), Folder 13.
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Correspondence, 1786 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Correspondence, Bond list for Catherine-Mary-Magdalen, Lots of Wawayanda Patent, 1787 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Correspondence, Property, 1788 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Box 19, William Beekman, 1789-1792
  For more detail, see White's guide, Volume 1, Pages 211-216.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, 1789 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, 1790 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, 1791 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, 1792 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Box 20, William Beekman, 1793-1798
  For additional information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 217-220.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, and Correspondence pertaining primarily to the disputed will of Mary Beekman., 1793-1794 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts and Correspondence pertaining largely to Mary Beekman's Estate and Wawayanda Patent., 1794 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes Chancery Court record for Mary Beekman's property case, 1794.
  - William Beekman, Family Accounts, Receipts and Correspondence relating largely to the Mary Beekman Estate dispute, 1795 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, Estate of William Beekman, Deceased, 1796 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1797 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1798 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Box 21, William Beekman & Beekmantown Patent, 1799-1809
  For more detail, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 221-231. Every folder in this box is mostly composed of correspondence and requests for land purchase in the Plattsburgh(Beekmantown) patent. For more Beekmantown (Plattsburgh, NY) see Box 30(A) Folders 2, 6, and Box 34(A) Folders 1-8.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, and Correspondence relating largely to Beekmantown Patent, 1799 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, Wawayanda Property, Copy of Will of Hannah Courtney, Estate of William Beekman, 1800 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, William Beekman Estate, 1801 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1802 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1803 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1804 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, James Badgley Account Book Tracking Multiple Beekman Family Members' Accounts, 1805 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1806 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, 1807 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, Itemized List of 23 Lots of Beekmantown (Acreage), 1808-1809 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Box 22, William Beekman and Cornelia Beekman Walton, 1722-1791
  For more detail, see White's guide, Volume 1, pages 168-175.
  - William Beekman, Letters received regarding Cranbury accounts, referred to as "Cranberry Letters", 1764-1775 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - William Beekman, Bonds, Penal Bills, Letters of Administration, Indentures, and Correspondence, pertaining largely to accounts in default, 1772-1791 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - William Beekman, Richmond Accounts, 1769-1789 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Cornelia Beekman Walton, Bills and Receipts pertaining largely to her annuity, 1774-1789 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Cornelia Beekman Walton, Correspondence regarding Property and Inheritance, Estate Inventories, and Accounts, Bulk, 1783-1786; 1768-1790 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Box 23, William Beekman, 1761-1820
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 1, pages 166-167.
  - Property Deeds of Clear Everitt, Wife Magdalen Everitt, and Nephew Gerard Rutgers in Dutchess County and Rhode Island, 1785 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Documents Regarding the Contested Will of Mary Beekman and Robert Rutger's Inheritance, 1784-1820 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Accounts, Legal Documents, and Probate Material for Tolmie and Barnes Families, 1763-1804 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Items are fragile and in poor condition.
  - William Beekman, Bills and Receipts, 1770-1785 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Accounts of Catherine Beekman, Mary Beekman, and William Beekman, 1783-1787 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - William Beekman, Daybooks, 1761-1769, 1783, 1788 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, and Estate Settlement Pertaining largely to the Tolmie Family, 1786-1808 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Materials are fragile and in poor condition.
- Box 24(A), William Beekman & James Beekman, Jr., 1696-1810
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 257-262.
  The Complaint of James Beekman, Jr. (1834) regarding the estate of his wife Lydia Beekman, and the Beekman Coat of Arms have been moved to oversized materials, Folder 2.
  - William Beekman, Bonds and Mortgages, 1766-1772 (Box 24(A), Folder 1)
  - William Beekman and the Rebuilding of Princeton's Nassau Hall, 1802-1807 (Box 24(A), Folder 2)
  - Elizabeth Rutgers and Rutgers Family, Accounts and Receipts, 1783-1790 (Box 24(A), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Pertaining to the Wawayanda Patent, 1766-1784 (Box 24(A), Folder 4)
  - William Beekman and Abraham Beekman, Bills and Receipts pertaining to Accounts in New Jersey, 1775-1783 (Box 24(A), Folder 5)
  - Nicholas Bayard, Supreme Court Judgments, Accounts, and Mortgages pertaining largely to insolvency, 1789-1792 (Box 24(A), Folder 6)
  - William Beekman, Houses on Dock and Duke Street, 1784-1790 (Box 24(A), Folder 7)
  - Deeds of Partition and Surveys of the Drowned Lands, a portion of the Wawayanda Patent, 1772-1806 (Box 24(A), Folder 8)
  - Bond, Correspondence, Mortgage, and Estate Settlement for Michael Moore and his wife, for 100 Acres in Hackensack, New Jersey, 1774-1805 (Box 24(A), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Jr. Overseas Business Papers, 1800-1810 (Box 24(A), Folder 10)
  - Various DeLancey Accounts, 1696-1773 (Box 24(A), Folder 11)
- Box 24(B), William Beekman & Samuel Beekman, 1755-1815
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 257-262 (Note: the account book described as being in Folder 16 has been moved to oversized materials).
  - Ship Log from Ship Levant, 1755 (Box 24(B), Folder 12)
  - Samuel Beekman, Indentures and Accounts with Sister Cornelia Beekman, Bulk, 1804-1815; 1769-1890 (Box 24(B), Folder 13)
  - William Beekman and Family, Bills and Receipts, 1761-1767 (Box 24(B), Folder 14)
  - Elizabeth Rutgers, Elizabeth Wainwright, and Family, Bills and Receipts, 1765-1777 (Box 24(B), Folder 15)
- Box 25(A), James W. Beekman, 1838-1851
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 263-299. Folders 4-9 contain correspondence mostly concerning NY State Legislature. Archive Page noting that Survey of Union cemetery and "the Beekman Crest" moved to Oversize Box, Folder 4.
  - American Colonization Society, Book of Resolutions of All State Legislatures "In Favor" of ACS, Circa 1830s (Box 25(A), Folder 1)
  - Public School Quizzes, 1850 (Box 25(A), Folder 2)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, Invitations, Calling Cards, and Other Ephemera Pertaining Largely to Travel (in French and German), Abstract of Will of William Beekman, Book of Exchange Rates, 1838-1839 (Box 25(A), Folder 3)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, 1850 (Box 25(A), Folder 4)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, Hamilton Fish Reelection, Booklet on Prussian Military Structure, January 1851 (Box 25(A), Folder 5)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, Juvenile Asylum, Hamilton Fish Reelection, February 2-14, 1851 (Box 25(A), Folder 6)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, Hamilton Fish Reelection, February 15-28, 1851 (Box 25(A), Folder 7)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, March 1-15, 1851 (Box 25(A), Folder 8)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, Copy of Supplement to NJ Registry Act (1 Document), March 1 to April 15, 1851 (Box 25(A), Folder 9)
- Box 25(B), James W. Beekman, 1849-1876
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, April 1 to June 30, 1851 (Box 25(B), Folder 10)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence Pertaining Primarily to Congressional Business, July 1 to December 31, 1851 (Box 25(B), Folder 11)
  - James W. Beekman and the Legislature, including Maxwell Correspondence, Jones Woods Park Petition, and Miscellaneous Legal Materials, February 1851 to March 1851 (Box 25(B), Folder 12)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, Circulars, 1852 (Box 25(B), Folder 13)
  - James W. Beekman, Cancelled Checks, Bills, and Other Accounts, 1865-1876 (Box 25(B), Folder 14)
    Materials listed in Folder 14 are not detailed in White's guide.
  - Minutes of the Select Committee to Investigate Abuses in Opening Streets in City of New York, 1849 (Box 25(B), Folder 15)
- Box 26(A), James W. Beekman, 1845-1900
  For additional detail, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 320-322.
  - Accounts and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1845-1857 (Box 26(A), Folder 1)
  - James W. Beekman, Political Petitions and Circulars, 1850-1863 (Box 26(A), Folder 2)
  - Political Documents Regarding Schools, Police, Asylums, and Churches, 1850-1851 (Box 26(A), Folder 3)
  - James W. Beekman, Real Estate Documents, 1850-1900 (Box 26(A), Folder 4)
  - James W. Beekman and Gerard Beekman, Real Estate Documents and Correspondence, 1896-1899 (Box 26(A), Folder 5)
  - James W. Beekman and Gerard Beekman, Real Estate Documents and Correspondence, 1898-1899 (Box 26(A), Folder 6)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, Real Estate Documents, and Accounts, 1898-1900 (Box 26(A), Folder 7)
- Box 26(B). James W. Beekman, 1896-1900
  - James W. Beekman, Real Estate Documents and Related Correspondence, 1896-1900 (Box 26(B), Folder 8)
  - James W. Beekman, Real Estate Documents, Membership in Sons of the Revolution, 1898-1899 (Box 26(B), Folder 9)
- Box 27, William Beekman & James Beekman, 1719-1837
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 304-305 (Note: descriptions do not directly correspond to folder listings in the guide).
  - Norman Tolmie, Receipt Book, 1765-1785 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - John Beekman, Accounts, 1837 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Bound Volume
  - William Beekman, Account Book, 1796-1808 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Receipt Book of Principle of Interest as Accounts of Rents Belonging to William Beekman, 1767-1773 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Beekman Family Cash Book, 1836 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, Jr., Letterbook, 1800 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Account Books, including Correspondence from Alexander Hamilton Regarding Richmond Estate Division, 1794-1797 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Mary Beekman, Estate Papers, 1793-1794 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Materials and Ephemera, Including "Items 16 and 17," Aldrich Drawing Entitled "The Cliffs," and Peter Beekman's Coat of Arms, Undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Field Book on Wawayanda Patent, Account Books, Cruise Ship Pamphlets, 1719-1804, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - James Beekman, Mathematical Tables, Account Book, Undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - List of Library of William Beekman, 1794 (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Box 28(A), Gerard Beekman, 1896-1922
  For more detail, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 323-325.
  - William Beekman and Gerard Beekman, Correspondence, Article Clippings, Real Estate and Church Related Documents, 1878-1902 (Box 28(A), Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents, Correspondence, Documents Regarding the Collegiate Dutch Church, Patents, 1896-1899 (Box 28(A), Folder 2)
    Includes request from Abraham Van Santvoord for a Century Club Recommendation.
  - Clippings, Correspondence, Invitations, Pamphlets, Church Expenses, Materials Pertaining to Boer War, 1900-1901 (Box 28(A), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Other Miscellaneous Materials Pertaining to the Boer War, Cruise Ships, and Horse Shows, 1902 (Box 28(A), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Other Miscellaneous Material, 1903 (Box 28(A), Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Church Budget, and Other Material Pertaining to the Presbyterian Hospital and New York Juvenile Asylum, 1904-1905 (Box 28(A), Folder 6)
  - Municipal Correspondence, Construction Receipts, Petitions, 1906-1922 (Box 28(A), Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Promotional Information on Mission Work, Legal Notes, Undated, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 28(A), Folder 8)
  - Church and Political Ephemera, Including Pamphlets and Business Cards, Circa 1878-1900s (Box 28(A), Folder 9)
- Box 28(B), Gerard Beekman, 1892-1904
  - Correspondence, Information on Cruise Ships, Miscellaneous Clippings, 1897-1903 (Box 28(B), Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents, Ephemera Pertaining Largely to the Dutch Reformed Church, 1892-1904 (Box 28(B), Folder 11)
- Box 29, Gerard Beekman, 1867-1913
  For additional information, see White's Guide, Volume 2, pages 326-327.
  - Papers Regarding the Yacht "Mirth II," Including Plans, Blueprints, Social Invitations, Newspaper Clippings, and Materials Pertaining to the New York Yacht Club, 1899-1913 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Drawings and Plans for "The Cliffs" in Oyster Bay, 1899-1902 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Drawings and Plans for "The Cliffs", 1899-1908 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Information Pertaining to Gerard Beekman's Patents, Including Drawings, Correspondence, and Legal Documents, 1896-1902 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Patents, Drawings, Correspondence, Legal Documents, 1898-1900 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Columbia University, Trustee and Commencement Ephemera, 1897-1905 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University, Correspondence, Trustee, and Commencement Ephemera, 1867-1913 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Box 30(A), James W. Beekman, 1839-1859
  For more information, see White's Guide, Volume 2, pages 300-301 (Note: some material in the guide, particularly bound volumes, is not designated by folder and has been relocated to Box 30(B)). For more on Beekmantown (folders 2, 6) see Box 21 Folders 1-10, and Box 34(A) Folder 2.
  - Invitations to Washington's Birthday Celebration, Account of Fraud in Assessments in NYC, Memo Book, Gerard Beekman's Notes on Professor Joy's Lectures, 1847-1848 (Box 30(A), Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts, Power of Attorney, Tax Assessments, Plan of Foundation for 51 St. House, Beekmantown Ephemera, James W. Beekman Income Assessment, Legal Documents, 1839-1849 (Box 30(A), Folder 2)
  - Accounts, Taxes, Checks, French Accounts (In French), 1850-1855 (Box 30(A), Folder 3)
  - Accounts Pertaining to European Trip, Largely from France, Some from Italy, 1856 (Box 30(A), Folder 4)
  - Accounts and Insurance Policy Material, Checks, Hand-Edited Copy of NY Senate Act for Local Improvements, 1857-1859 (Box 30(A), Folder 5)
  - Accounts, Family Purchases of Dry Goods, State Senate Papers, Map of Beekmantown Lot-holders, 1859 (Box 30(A), Folder 6)
- Box 30(B), James W. Beekman, 1833-1875
  - Bills Paid, Including Grammar School Receipts, 1859-1860 (Box 30(B), Folder 7)
  - Bills Paid, Including Accounts of Dutch Reformed Church, 1860 (Box 30(B), Folder 8)
  - Passport, 1838 (Box 30(B), Folder 9)
  - Expense Books, 1841-1846 (Box 30(B), Folder 10)
  - Account Books of Accounts with Grocers, Butchers, Waiters, and Coachmen, 1859-1867 (Box 30(B), Folder 11)
  - Bank and Account Books, 1833-1867 (Box 30(B), Folder 12)
  - Letter Acknowledging James W. Beekman as a Trustee of Columbia College, 1875 (Box 30(B), Folder 13)
  - List of Expenses, 1860-1867 (Box 30(B), Folder 14)
- Box 31(A), Gerard Beekman and William Beekman, 1722-1818
  For more detail, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 252-256 (Note: materials do not all directly correspond to folder listings in the guide as they were divided into three separate boxes).
  - Gerard Beekman, Property and Indentures, 1722-1795 (Box 31(A), Folder 1)
  - Deeds Pertaining to Beekmantown, 1799-1808 (Box 31(A), Folder 2)
  - William Beekman, Correspondence and Bonds Related to Property and Estate Settlement, 1763-1813 (Box 31(A), Folder 3)
  - William Beekman, Bonds, Leases, and Indentures, 1755-1796 (Box 31(A), Folder 4)
  - William Beekman, Wrappings (Indentures) and Bills of Sale, Undated (Box 31(A), Folder 5)
  - William Beekman and Catherine Boudinot, Accounts and Estate Information, Chancery Records, Bound Volumes Listing Stock Dividends, 1797-1818 (Box 31(A), Folder 6)
  - William Beekman, Accounts and Estate Information, 1799 (Box 31(A), Folder 7)
- Box 31(B), William Beekman, 1744-1819
  - Legal Documents Pertaining to the Wawayanda Patent and Family Property, Including Indenture of Elizabeth Rutgers, 1791, 1756-1805 (Box 31(B), Folder 8)
  - Legal Documents, Indentures, Bills of Sale, Many Pertaining to the Water Lot, 1753-1795 (Box 31(B), Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents, Releases, 1744-1819 (Box 31(B), Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents, Deeds in Trust, Division of Troup's Farm, 1753-1812 (Box 31(B), Folder 11)
- Box 31(C), William Beekman and James Beekman, 1757-1822
  - Legal Documents, Probate Materials of William Beekman, Deeds for Bayard, Coens, Livingston, and Ludlow Families, 1757-1801 (Box 31(C), Folder 12)
  - James Beekman and Jane Beekman, Account Books Pertaining to Sundry Accounts and Rent, 1796-1814 (Box 31(C), Folder 13)
  - James Beekman, Account and Estate Information, Including Bound Volumes Pertaining Largely to the Heirs of Beekman's Estate, 1804-1816 (Box 31(C), Folder 14)
  - Descriptions of Household and Kitchen Furniture and Wearing Apparel, Circa 1790s-1820s (Box 31(C), Folder 15)
- Box 32(A), James Beekman, 1786-1793
  For additional description, see White's guide, Volume 1, pages 142-159.
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence Pertaining Largely to Business in Europe, 1885-1786 (Box 32(A), Folder 1)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1787 (Box 32(A), Folder 2)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1788 (Box 32(A), Folder 3)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1789 (Box 32(A), Folder 4)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1789 (Box 32(A), Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1790 (Box 32(A), Folder 6)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1791 (Box 32(A), Folder 7)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1793 (Box 32(A), Folder 8)
- Box 32(B), James Beekman, & Box 33, Beekman Family Property & Correspondence, 1713-1799
  For more on the "Drew Affair" (folder 11), see Box 34(A) Folders 1-8.
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Property, Receipts, 1794 (Box 32(B), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Chancery Court Expenses, 1795 (Box 32(B), Folder 10)
  - James Beekman, Jr., Drew Affair, 1798-1799 (Box 32(B), Folder 11)
    Contains material described in the guide as being in Folder 13
  - James Beekman and Jane Keteltas, Accounts and Estate Lists, Book Containing the "History of the World in Major Events Since its Creation in 4004 B.C.", Undated (Box 32(B), Folder 12)
  - James Beekman, Early Deeds Regarding the Wawayanda Patent, Miscellaneous Receipts, 1713-1818 (Box 32(B), Folder 13)
  - Maps of Beekman Properties, Circa 1750s (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Leases to Ernest Conrad and John B. Morrel, 1849, 1857 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    Items in this folder are not described in White's guide.
  - Envelopes and Wrappings for Letters, Undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Box 34(A), James Beekman, 1800-1819
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 1, pages 160-161 (Note: descriptions are mainly for international affairs and property, and are not organized in order). Beekmantown documents in Folder 2. See also Box 21 Folders 10-10, Box 30(A) Folders 2,6. "Drew Affair" in folders 1-8, and for the origins of the Drew Affair, see Box 32(B) Folder 11.
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1800 (Box 34(A), Folder 1)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Receipts, "Drew Affair," Beekmantown, 1801 (Box 34(A), Folder 2)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Receipts, "Drew Affair", 1802 (Box 34(A), Folder 3)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, "Drew Affair", 1803 (Box 34(A), Folder 4)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, "Drew Affair", 1804 (Box 34(A), Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, "Drew Affair", 1805 (Box 34(A), Folder 6)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, "Drew Affair," James Beekman Estate Papers, 1806 (Box 34(A), Folder 7)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, "Drew Affair," Property Documents, 1807 (Box 34(A), Folder 8)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Map of City Lots, James Beekman Estate Property Valuation, 1808 (Box 34(A), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, Indentures, Receipts, Insurance, Carriage Tax, 1810-1815 (Box 34(A), Folder 10)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Receipts, 1816 (Box 34(A), Folder 11)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Receipts, Clipping from the NY Daily Advertiser dated 9/1/1817 (Box 34(A), Folder 12)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, 1818 (Box 34(A), Folder 13)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, Property Papers, Receipts, 2 Blank Copies of "Sea Officers' Widows' Charity", 1819 (Box 34(A), Folder 14)
- Box 34(B), James Beekman, 1799-1839
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, and Subscriptions, 1820-1829 (Box 34(B), Folder 15)
  - James Beekman and Lydia Beekman, Correspondence Regarding Royal Navy Pension, 1820-1825 (Box 34(B), Folder 15A)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, and Subscriptions, 1830 (Box 34(B), Folder 16)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Subscriptions, and Documents Regarding Pension, 1831 (Box 34(B), Folder 17)
  - James Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, and Subscriptions, 1832 (Box 34(B), Folder 18)
  - James Beekman, Indentures and Agreements, 1827-1834 (Box 34(B), Folder 19)
  - James Beekman, Property Information, 1799-1801, 1837-1839 (Box 34(B), Folder 20)
    Description of contents listed in White's guide, Volume 1, page 164.
- Box 35(A), Estate Papers, 1763-1839
  For more information, see White's guide, Volume 2, pages 306-310 (Note: includes description of materials pertaining to business and property, including shipping, mercantile accounts, and the Chancery Court).
  - Cornelia Beekman Walton, Estate, 1763-1800 (Box 35(A), Folder 1)
  - Gerard Beekman, Samuel Beekman, and James Beekman, Correspondence, 1803-1822 (Box 35(A), Folder 2)